<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <!-- Precautions Can Improve Survivability -->
    <string-array name="before_earthquake">
	    <item>
	        Identify the most structurally secure areas of your workplace and home. 
	        These are usually spots located away from windows and large moveable objects.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        Commit to memory these secure areas,
	        which include spaces under desks,
	        tables,
	        or benches or door frames on inside walls,
	        and be prepared to use them during an earthquake.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        Many workplaces hold earthquake emergency drills 
	        and you should do the same at home with family members 
	        if you live in an earthquake zone.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        At work and at home, 
	        ensure that you’re not sitting or 
	        standing in the path of an object such as a 
	        large bookcase or filing cabinet, 
	        which could tip over and crush you during a strong earthquake. 
	        Heavy, tip-prone objects should be bolted or wired tightly to walls. 
	        Never hang mirrors or other heavy objects above where people sit, 
	        work or sleep.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        At home, prepare an earthquake emergency kit 
	        containing non-perishable food, water, medicine, 
	        first aid supplies, batteries, a flashlight, 
	        a battery-powered or crank-powered radio, clothing and money.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        Take training in cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) 
	        and first aid.
	    </item>
      </string-array>
    <!-- What Should I do During an Earthquake? -->
    <string-array name="during_earthquake">
	    <item>
	        Immediately take cover under a heavy object such as a desk and 
	        place your hands over your head. Brace yourself using your feet. 
	        Don’t try to run outside, 
	        where you might be struck by falling debris or power lines.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        If you’re outside when an earthquake strikes, 
	        move to an open area away from buildings, 
	        trees and power lines.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        If you’re near an ocean beach where a strong earthquake 
	        may have generated a tsunami, 
	        quickly move to higher ground.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        Stay away from elevators during an earthquake, 
	        but if you’re inside one, 
	        press the buttons for all floors and 
	        get out as quickly as possible.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        If you’re in your car or work vehicle, 
	        pull over away from bridges, 
	        overpasses and buildings. 
	        Stay in your vehicle until the quake ends.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        If you’re in a crowded space, 
	        stay away from doors. 
	        People may panic and bolt, 
	        rampling others.
	    </item>
    </string-array>
    <!-- What to do Once the Quake Ends -->
    <string-array name="after_earthquake">
	    <item>
	        Rely only on emergency lighting or flashlights. 
	        Don’t turn on any other lights, 
	        since leaking natural gas lines could cause an explosion.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        Get outside to a clear, open area away from any structures 
	        that might suddenly collapse. This area should be designated 
	        as part of your employer’s emergency preparedness plan and 
	        all workers should know to gather there for a head count.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        Check yourself and others for injuries and 
	        call for necessary emergency help.
	    </item>
	    <item>
	        Never re-enter a damaged building after an earthquake. 
	        It could be weakened and collapse without warning hours or days later.
	     </item>
	     <item>
	         Expect aftershocks in the hours and 
	         days following an earthquake.
	     </item>
     </string-array>
     <!-- What You Should Do - In the event of a Flood Watch or Warning:  -->
     <string-array name="during_flood">
	     <item>
	         Follow announced radio, 
	         television, or 
	         emergency vehicle instructions.
	     </item>
	     <item>
	         If a Flash Flood Warning was issued and you are in a mountainous area: 
				 Climb to high ground as fast as possible. 
				 Do not try to take your gear with you - your life is more important! 
				 Do not try to run or drive downhill to outrace a flash flood.
	     </item>
	     <item>
	         	If a Flood Warning was issued and you are in the mapped floodplain 
	         	Turn off the electricity and gas if necessary. 
	         	Read Flood Safety Outdoors on the back cover.
	         	Lock your doors and evacuate to higher ground.
	         	If you do not have a safe place to stay on high ground,
	         	listen to the radio or TV for information on public shelter locations 
	     </item>
	     <item>
	         If you are not in the mapped floodplain, but your basement floods: 
				 Turn off the basement electricity. 
				 Turn off the gas, if you expect the pilot light to be flooded. 
				 Move valuables upstairs. 
				 Stay out of the basement, if floodwater is touching the house outside
	     </item>
     </string-array>
     <!-- After the Flood  -->
     <string-array name="after_flood">
	     <item >
	         Keep the family together. 
	         Togetherness provides 	mutual support. 
	     </item>
	     <item>
	         Rest often and eat well. You are more likely to 
			 suffer from stress and health problems 
			 when you are weak.
	     </item>
	     <item>
	         Set a manageable schedule. 
	         Make a prioritized 
	         list of jobs to do one at a time.
	     </item>
	     <item>
	         Stay healthy. When you work in an area that has been flooded, 
	         you probably will be exposed to dangerous chemicals and germs. 
	         Minimize contact with floodwater and debris by wearing protective clothing, 
	         like rubber boots and gloves, a mask or respirator. 
	     </item>
	     <item>
	         Flood proof as you rebuild. 
	         Nobody likes being subject to the whims of nature. 
	         Preparing for a future flood can increase your sense of control over your destiny. 
	     </item>
	</string-array>
</resources>
